Finding Aid for the Nicholas E. Collias Papers Biomed.0432
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Professional organization records, 1958-2007
  - International Ornithological Congress application and poster, 1990, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Cooper Ornithological Program and ALBS paper, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - International Ornithological Congress Program, 1962 (Box 4, Folder 64)
  - Southern California Behavioral Ecology and Sociobiology Study Group, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - Entomological societies' newsletters, circa 1989 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Animal Behavior Society: Autobiographical Surveys, 1996 (Box 8, Folder 27-28)
  - Animal Behavior Society presentation materials, 1993-1994 (Box 9, Folder 1-15, Box 4, Folder 23-24)
    Animal Behavior Society talk by Nicholas E. Collias and Elsie C. Collias. Copies of slides, graphs, tables, outline and lecture. These materials were also used for their 1994 American Ornithologists' Union presentation.
  - Awards and honors, 1958-2007 (Box 8, Folder 22, Box 6, Folder 2)
    Awards and honors from various organizations including UCLA Emeriti Association, Natural History Museum of Los Angeles County, American Institute of Biological Sciences, Cooper Ornithological Society, American Ornithologists' Union and the Animal Behavior Society.
- United States Army Air Forces publications, 1943-1945
  After Collias earned his PhD in 1942, he was drafted into the U.S. Army where he spent three and a half years. He rose from the rank of private to first lieutenant and finished his Army career as a medical research physiologist. These publications include Collias' annotations.
  - Outline of Neuropsychiatry in Aviation Medicine, circa 1944 (Box 4, Folder 65)
  - Notes on Men and Groups Under Stress of Combat: For the Use of Flight Surgeons in Operational Units, 1945 (Box 4, Folder 65)
  - How Can the Flight Surgeon Better Treat Anxiety?, 1945 (Box 4, Folder 65)
  - Care of Personnel in the Wet Tropics, 1944 (Box 4, Folder 65)
  - Living Off the Land, circa 1943 (Box 4, Folder 65)
  - Living Off the Southwest Pacific Tropics, 1944 (Box 4, Folder 65)
  - High Altitude Frostbite, 1943 (Box 4, Folder 66)
  - Aviation Physiologists Bulletin, 1945 (Box 4, Folder 66)
  - Physiology of Flight: Human Factors in the Operation of Military Aircraft, 1945 (Box 4, Folder unknown container, Folder 66)
  - Your Body in Flight, 1943 (Box 4, Folder 66)